The SCOAN Sunday Service
Good morning, Church!
Good morning.
Viewers all over the world, Good Morning!
Hallelujah!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
- Hallelujah!
- Amen.
Don’t forget – today is the last meeting before the birthday.
This is an opportunity to let you know whom you are celebrating.
How do we celebrate this kind of man?
You can see, he is not a superstar.
He is a man of people.
If he is a man of people, let us look for people who need what we have.
People who are in need – look for them; that is how to celebrate him.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Thank you.
I must give that honour and respect for the little ones.
Hallelujah.
Today is the last Sunday before the celebration.
You know you were born on June 12th!
- Hallelujah.
- Amen.
You have many things to watch in terms of videos and recordings
concerning the man you are seeing today, your little brother, T.B. Joshua.
Thank you.
Right from the beginning of the ministry at the time you got to know T.B. Joshua,
you will study that humility because I found myself in a simple and humble family background.
That is what is reflecting in me.
When I say humble, simple, I mean, lacking basic needs of life.
To lack the basic needs of life, you know what it means.
I am going to show you the humble home I came from.
We still preserve this home.
When you go to my village, you will find it just the same.
I said, "No. Don't touch it. Leave it."
Let us see the humble home.
THIS IS THE PICTURE OF OUR HUMBLE HOME
That is my humble home I came from.
It is still there; we preserved it.
I said, "No. Don't touch it."
There was a very strong force which God is behind -
kept telling me that what I was going through was a preparation for my future.
I mean, a strong force I could not resist.
As I am standing here, there is a force that is telling me
that what you are going through right now may not be found tomorrow.
In those early years of my life, I knew I would be blamed if I gave my attention
to what I was going through.
Consequently, I did not want my focus to be broken.
I chose to direct my focus on the right path, on what is right
because of the strong force that was directing me; I could not resist that force.
As I am standing now, there is a force I cannot resist which God is behind.
I cannot resist; it is telling me...
Each time I try to go wrong, it will say to me, "No. Go this way."
Anytime I felt I was missing my focus, it became a very strong motivation to pray
and be closer to God.
As a human being, there must be...
But anytime - it became a very strong motivation to pray to God, and to be closer to God.
It was still the same strong, mighty force that kept telling me,
“Concentrate on your future. Ignore the present.
Concentrate on your future; ignore what you are going through.
Concentrate on your future because what you are going through may not be found tomorrow”.
CONCENTRATE ON YOUR FUTURE
Concentrate on your future.
What you are going through is a preparation for your future, a bridge to your future.
The more I prayed, the less people would see me and the more isolated I became.
This affected all of my social life.
In those days, my colleagues and friends around complained
that I was not social and civilised enough like them.
That was their complain, "That guy - leave him. Let him go."
That kept me isolated.
They complained I was not social and civilised enough like them.
In this way, wrong, mistakes became an incentive that drew me closer to God
instead of otherwise.
Tell your neighbour, “If you make a mistake, don’t run from God; run to Him”.
Wrong became an incentive that drew me closer to God.
Whatever you are going through now, listen to me.
Whatever your present challenge is now, whatever your tribulation or condition,
it’s merely a preparation for your future.
It may not be found tomorrow because it is a preparation for your future.
That is why it may not be found.
Tell your neighbour, “Whatever I am going through, whatever the challenge or difficulty,
it may not be found tomorrow because it is a preparation for the future."
What are you going through?
You just need to know this.
Like I have told you, there was a force I could not resist.
I tried to resist, but each time the voice, "No. Do this."
I could not resist it.
The voice kept telling me, “Concentrate on your future
because the situation you are in now may not be found tomorrow”.
Once again, Happy Birthday in advance!
I was a baby before the death of my father.
You know little baby before the death of my father.
Consequently, I knew nothing about my late father
and the entire family burden rested squarely on my mother’s shoulder.
Let them show you the picture of my late father.
THIS IS THE PICTURE OF MY LATE FATHER, G.K. BALOGUN
THIS IS THE PICTURE OF MY LATE MOTHER, FOLARIN BALOGUN WHO GAVE ME HER LAST HUG
This is my mum; the last hug, "Bye bye", given to me.
Hallelujah.
I want to pay a special tribute to my late mother,
who always advised me to look into my love walk.
Failing to do so can shut down our relationship with God.
I salute her.
What a wonderful woman!
She never failed to call us for prayer before going to bed.
When I was baby...
It was a must, a duty; she called us for prayer before going to bed.
Don’t forget – prayer from the heart is Spirit prayer; it leads to dreams and revelations.
That really helped greatly; the impact was so great.
I often dreamt; I was always taught the Scriptures in the dream ‘til now.
That gave me an urge; over...
I was the smallest boy in my class but always led prayer.
When you look at the picture, you will see me very little among them, but I always led the prayer.
My teachers and colleagues always called me ‘small pastor’.
I think some of you might have watched the video in the past; they always called me 'small pastor'.
In human life, many things could cause one to stop between steps.
For example, my educational career suffered epileptic fits.
What I mean by 'epileptic fits'?
Today I am in school, the next day out.
I was very smart and brilliant but the reason was beyond me.
I attended six colleges in less than one year.
If I may begin with...
My first college was Ansar-Ud-Deen Grammar School, Ikare (AUD).
From there, I left the village back to Lagos in a mysterious way.
There are many records I am still keeping for 60, 70, 80, 90!
Because I know you keep asking yourself, “Why now is this man showing this record?”
Yes.
Now, I started at the age of 55; another record at 60; I keep so many.
I am going to show you just 10 percent of those records today.
I began my college at Ansar-Ud-Deen Grammar School in Ikare, called AUD, in a mysterious way.
I was one of the 'late candidates', 'late admission'.
I was in E class, classes were not supposed to extend to E, they stopped at D.
I spent nine months and left mysteriously back to Lagos.
When I came to Lagos, the first college I attended was Metropolitan College in Isolo.
I was there for three months.
I left to New State High School and spent one month there.
From New State High School, I went to Bishop Aggrey College where I spent three months.
From there to Ikotun, there is a college where we were the first students there; it was called Muslim College.
I spent three months also there.
All this happened in less than one year.
I was moving from...
The reason was beyond me, I will not be able to explain it.
The first college - I can only share this with you because of time.
At the first college AUD in Ikare, suddenly one night at 3am, I never knew what took me out.
I was on the street at 3am, just going on the street.
It was a watchman who saw me, rescued my life and placed me at his duty post until daybreak.
He later took me to the authorities in the school to explain.
Then, I was 'half-balanced'.
I could not continue my education; back to my mummy.
I spent another two years at home.
That is one; I will not be able to tell you about the others because of time; at 60 I will share with you.
HAPPY BIRTHDAY T.B. JOSHUA AT 55!!!
I attended six colleges in less than one year.
I told you this; whatever you are going through now, whatever situation you are in
may not be found tomorrow because it is a preparation for your future.
Tell your neighbour.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Whatever you are going through, whatever you are facing
may not be found tomorrow because it is a preparation for your future,
to link you to the future.
Now, I want to begin to show you some records. Let me start from my birth.
The record I am about to show you is not saying I have arrived
but to encourage the weak and those without fast legs or human help
that there is hope – Jesus is the hope.
I stayed in my mother’s womb for fifteen months.
At nine months, my mother was moving from one medical centre to another
because she was in labour.
From nine months, my mother began labour and she was moving from one medical centre
to another hospital until she was carried to a place called Egbe Medical Centre.
At that time, it seemed to be the best hospital in Nigeria, if not one of the best.
Go to the record.
So, let's see the picture of the hospital where my mummy finally delivered me.
THIS IS THE PICTURE OF EGBE HOSPITAL, WHERE I WAS BORN AT LAST
AFTER MY MOTHER VISITED MANY MEDICAL CENTRES
Yes.
When I was delivered and about to be named on the seventh day in a naming ceremony,
arrangements were made and many guests turned up who wanted to see a child
who spent fifteen months in his mother’s womb.
You can imagine the number of people that were present.
In our village, there is so much rock that needs to be blasted before getting water.
It became a habit; everyday, they had to blast to get water from the ground.
Opposite the house where I was about to be named,
there was a company that was blasting rocks for water.
Suddenly, a very big stone...
You cannot imagine - the stone is here with me.
A big stone flew from the opposite direction straight to the same humble home
and landed on the exact net where I was lying.
What happened?
No one knows how Baby Joshua moved from the net to the other side of the room.
What happened to the mother?
She fainted, went into a coma and was carried to the hospital.
The guests and the people waiting for the ceremony were saying, "What happened?
We are here to see the child who spent 15 months in the womb and was delivered.
This is what happened.
The baby was saved."
Out of sheer wonder and surprise, they started voicing different names.
Temitope, Tope, Temidire, Temioluwa, Temidayo – different names.
I decided to choose Temitope out of those names.
Are you ready to watch the stone?
Yes.
OK, please watch.
The Town Where Prophet T.B. Joshua Was Brought Up – Arigidi, Ondo State, Nigeria
In 1963, a humble home, in a rural district of Arigidi, Ondo State, Nigeria, became the scene
of an incredible miracle; a child had finally been born, after 15 months in his mother's womb.
However, anything close to Jesus receives attack.
The devil attempted to snatch away this young life, just days later,
but what the devil meant for evil, God meant for good.
Moving through the compound, we arrive at the small house in which Prophet T.B. Joshua
was raised and spent his childhood days.
A closer inspection of the roof reveals a noticeably large hole.
What could possibly have happened to create such damage?
A Hole In The Roof Of Prophet T.B. Joshua’s Childhood Home In Arigidi, Ondo State, Nigeria
Peering through the hole, a jagged stone can be seen lying on the floor of this modest home.
Inside The Childhood Home Of Prophet T.B. Joshua
This is the small room, in which Prophet T.B. Joshua grew up with his family.
This is a house with a remarkable story to tell.
A Hole In The Roof Of Prophet T.B. Joshua’s Childhood Home In Arigidi, Ondo State, Nigeria
Let someone who was there that day tell you the story and unravel the mystery.
In the name of the Father, the Son and the Holy Spirit.
A water pipe was being dug at a nearby site and you were laid here, sleeping.
Shockingly, a stone flew from the site through this zinc and landed very close to where you were sleeping.
Where is the stone?
This is the very stone.
Has the stone been kept since then?
It is the very one. We did not throw it away ever since.
When they gave birth to you and you were about to be named.
This is where we all were sleeping and where we gave birth to all our children.
We did not sleep elsewhere.
If one could go outside, the broken part of the zinc that was covered is still visible.
You were laid here and the stone fell beside you.
Is this the particular stone?
This was the point it was broken.
Can you see it?
So, what happened to me?
Jesus rescued you and made you healthy.
I didn’t throw it away. It is part of history.
Somebody advised me to smoothen it and use it as a grinding stone but I refused
because of the mysterious and miraculous role God used it to play in this family.
It wasn’t like this on the day the incident occurred.
Eventually, however, we shall create a special box for the stone.
This was how you were laid on the ground; your mother slept close to you.
There was a local lamp near your mother’s head and a fire used to treat your mother’s stomach.
The stone suddenly crashed down near you. Before God and man, that was what happened.
Glory be to the name of the Lord.
Elderly Women Sing Songs Of Praise To God
I am his step-mother.
HAPPY BIRTHDAY T.B. JOSHUA AT 55!!!
Prophet T.B. Joshua’s Childhood Home In Arigidi, Ondo State, Nigeria
The stone they found when they were blasting rock – this is it.
HAPPY BIRTHDAY T.B. JOSHUA AT 55!!!
The Stone That Flew Through The Roof And Landed Next To Where T.B. Joshua Lay At 7 Days Old
This is the stone; this is T.B. Joshua!
Thank you.
HAPPY BIRTHDAY T.B. JOSHUA AT 55!!!
I’m older than the stone, by seven days!
It came out on the seventh day, when I was about to be named.
So, the stone must be fifty...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Thank you.
Like I have said; we are not showing you this because we are saying we have arrived but
it is an encouragement to the weak, to those without fast legs and
those without human help, the under-privileged, that there is hope and Jesus is the hope.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So, we will begin to show you from where the ministry started and the name - Synagogue Church of All Nations,
the foundation of the church; we will show you now - you will see.
All this is not acting; it’s real.
It’s a real record.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Walks Through The Town And Children Follow Him
Hallelujah!
Let us be seated.
Amen!
In fact, I don’t know where to start.
My coming into your midst is just to lay a foundation.
I am here to lay a foundation – that today, we start The Synagogue here!
Amen!
Hallelujah!
The Synagogue has started here!
I have come to launch a good foundation for the church.
Amen!
You should know that this man always says things in proverbs.
They say that Jesus is coming.
All the elders here have been hearing from a young age that Jesus is coming.
We have been expecting His coming up until now and we are still preparing for it.
The reason Jesus has not come is because He wants you and I to repent from our sins
because He doesn’t want anyone to perish.
Have you repented?
HAPPY BIRTHDAY T.B. JOSHUA AT 55!!!
Hallelujah!
The reason the coming of Jesus is delayed is because God wants you to repent.
Repent from your sin, so that you will not perish.
By the time Jesus comes, you will not perish; you will inherit the Kingdom of God.
Right from your childhood, you have been learning that Jesus will come like a thief in the night.
We have been waiting for the coming of Jesus.
The reason the coming of Jesus has been delayed is because of you and me.
Jesus wants you to repent; He doesn’t want you to perish.
By the time He comes, He can carry you to eternal life.
If Jesus should come and you have not repented, the coming of Jesus in your life has no meaning.
In order for the coming of Jesus to have meaning in your life, you need to repent.
You have to repent today and accept Jesus,
so that when Jesus comes, you can join Him in the Kingdom of God.
So, for me and my house – and I believe you are my house – we will serve the Lord.
Clap for Jesus!
Hallelujah!
We thank God. Even if you want me to prostrate for you, I am ready!
Prophet T.B. Joshua Digs A Drainage System At The Synagogue, Church Of All Nations
Prophet T.B. Joshua And Workers Fill And Carry Buckets With Sand To Work At The SCOAN
During Another Work Day At The SCOAN Prophet T.B. Joshua Takes A Break To Eat
Prophet T.B. Joshua Warms Up In Front Of The Fire During A Long Day Of Work At The SCOAN
Prophet T.B. Joshua Spends Time With The Sunday School Children And Eats With Them
Sunday School Children And Their Parents Enjoy Spending Time With Prophet T.B. Joshua
Prophet T.B. Joshua Moving Among The Congregation During The SCOAN Sunday Service
Prophet T.B. Joshua Serves Food To The Congregation During The Sunday Service
The SCOAN Service Begins As Prophet T.B. Joshua Is Busy Cleaning The Chairs In The Auditorium
Prophet T.B. Joshua Weaving Native Baskets
Prophet T.B. Joshua Joins The Youth In A Game Of Football
This is the picture of Egbe hospital, where I was born at last after my mother visited many medical centres.
This is a picture of our humble home.
This is the picture of my late father, G.K. Balogun.
This is the picture of my late mother, Folarin Balogun who gave me her last hug.
LEISURE TIME WITH PROPHET TB JOSHUA
Leisure time with Prophet T.B. Joshua.
Playing with nature is a leisure time with nature to ease tension and stress.
Leisure Time With Prophet T.B. Joshua
I want to encourage you to often find a natural environment to read your Bible
because natural environment is natural and free from distraction.
Nature itself enhances spirituality.
I often read my Bible in a calm and quiet environment
because the Bible is not like other books you can read anywhere and understand.
Understanding of the Bible is understanding the nature of God.
Leisure Time With Prophet T.B. Joshua
It must be read in an enabling environment to understand it.
To live it, it must be read in an enabling environment.
To teach it, it can be read anywhere.
Leisure Time With Prophet T.B. Joshua
Leisure time - time to be refreshed and be renewed.
God's Word refreshes our mind, God's Spirit renews our strength.
Leisure Time With Prophet T.B. Joshua
You can now see the kind of man you are celebrating is not a superstar;
he is a man of the people.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
How do we celebrate this kind of man?
You can see, he is not a superstar.
He is a man of people.
If he is a man of people, let us look for people who need what we have.
People who are in need – look for them; that is how to celebrate him.
He is a man of people.
The man we are seeing is a man of people.
There is no way a man can be raised in such a simple and humble family background
and now turn to a superstar; it is not possible.
This is a man of people; to celebrate him, you must look for those who are in need,
people that are in need of what you have – your love, your care – look for them.
Someone is out there who needs your care.
Someone is out there who needs your money.
Someone is out there who needs your love.
Someone is out there who needs your smile – look for them.
Thank you!
Happy Birthday!
TT Robert Begier 15/06/2018
RV: Mel Flowers 14/08/2018